[
{
  "question": "A cylinder rotates about its axis and lies perpendicular to the flow direction, explain the Magnus effect on the cylinder in terms of fluid velocity and experienced pressure. Note that the flow is incompressible and uniform.",
  "answer": "The Magnus effect influences the flow velocity by combining the velocity at the cylinder's surface with that of the fluid velocity of the flow on one side of the object while simultaneously reducint the velocity from the other side of the cylinder. From the resulting change of fluid velocity on the different sides of the cylinder and the known Bernoulli's principle explaining a faster fluid results in lower pressure, it can be discerned that the side of the cylinder with the faster fluid velocity will possess a lower pressure than the side of the cylinder with much slower fluid velocity (which would possess a higher pressure).",
  "reference": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnus_effect#:~:text=The%20Magnus%20effect%20is%20an,the%20object%20is%20not%20spinning."
},
{
  "question": "What is the difference between Eulerian and Lagrangian description for moving fluid particles? Which of the two uses advection in their respective equation?",
  "answer": "Lagrangian descriptions for fluid particles focuses on observing each particle as an individual, analyzing the properties of said particle at different times. Eulerian descriptions looks at the entire field of particles rather than individual points. Properties of the fluid and particles are looked at with respect to location and time instead of individual particles. Eulerian descriptions also use advection in their equation to describe particles."
},
{
  "question": "Describe how the Coanda effect plays a role in the streamline positions across the top of an airfoil when faced by a jet of fluid.",
  "answer": "The Coanda effect explains that this jet of fluid possesses a pressure below that of the atmosphere, which results in the moving fluid to attach itself closer to the top of the airfoil as the jet flows across it. This appears as though multiple streamlines wrap closer to the top of the airfoil and follow the physical dimension of it until the tail."
},
{
  "question": "What is the key characteristic of the following thermodynamic processes: Isochoric, isobarich, isothermal. What is the derivation for each process' external work?",
  "answer": "An isochoric process is one with constant volume, and with an absence of stirring in the process, the work performed is equal to 0. An isobaric process is one with constant pressure, and experiences work through a 'pdV' integral equal to 'mR(T2-T1)'. An isothermal process in one in which the temperature remains constant, and experiences work through a 'pdV' integral equal to 'mRT[Ln(V2/V1)].'"
},
{
  "question": "Which ways can fluid equilibrium be disturbed, note that this is in the absence of margnetic and electric fields. Explain at least one of these types of equilibrium.",
  "answer": "Fluid equilibrium is disturbed mechanically, compositionally, chemically, or thermally. Mechanical equilibrium is based in the unifromity between pressure and velocity."
},
{
  "question":"How do turbines and compressors work together to produce shaft work?",
  "answer":"The two work to produce shaft work by using the turbine to create a pressure gradient that falls across the system, extracting work and applying it through the compressor to increase the pressure of the fluid. The work exchange is achieved with airfoil-shaped blades within the compressor-turbine system. "
},
{
  "question":"Do the following properties increase, decrease, or remain constant across a shock wave: static temperature, statice pressure, work, heat, total enthalpy, density, and total temperature.",
  "answer": "A shock wave does no work and has no added heat, meaning they remain constant. Additionally the total enthalpy and total temperature across a shock are constant. Static pressure, static temperature, and density increase across the shock wave. Note that in the case of a shock that the total pressure downstream will always be less than the total pressure upstream, thus a pressure loss across the shock. "
},
{
  "question": "How do the following properties change across an oblique shock and expansion fan: Mach, density, static pressure, enthalpy, and stagnation pressure.",
  "answer":"For oblique shocks, the mach downstream is less than the mach upstream, the density downstream is greater than the density upstream, the pressure downstream is greater than the pressure upstream, the total enthalpy downstream is greater than the total enthalpy upstream, the stagnation pressure downstream is less than the stagnation pressure upstream. For expansion fans, the mach downstream is greater than the mach upstream, the density downstream is less than the density upstream, the pressure downstream is less than the pressure upstream, the total enthalpy downstream is less than the total enthalpy upstream, the stagnation pressure downstream is equal to the stagnation pressure upstream. "
},
{
  "question":"Describe the model for Fanno flow, elaborating any assumptions regarding the model and considerations.",
  "answer":"The Fanno flow model is used to consider compressible flows that experience friction, particularly in things like pipes or tubes. Assumptions about this flow include that the flow is steady, one-dimensional, is adiabatic, and, in the case of a duct/tube, the area is constant. Fanno flow is considered to be an irreversible process due to the effects of friction. Note that said friction is modeled to be similar to shear stress acting on the walls of the duct/tube. "
},
{
  "question": "Calculate the mass flows out of the tank with two inlets and one outlet. There are two liquids, possessing densities 300 kg/m^3 and 500 kg/m^3, respective to inlet 1 with an area of 0.5 m^2 and inlet 2 with an area of 1 m^2. Inlet 1 has a uniform fluid velocity of 4.4 m/s while inlet 2 has a uniform fluid velocity of 2.7 m/s.",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      rho1 = 300 # Density of fluid 1
      rho2= 500 # density of fluid 2
      A1= 0.5 # area of inlet 1
      A2= 1 # area of inlet 2
      v1= 4.4 # velocty of fluid in inlet 1
      v2= 2.7 # velocity of fluid in inlet 2  

      # mass flow rates for each respective inlet
      m1= rho1*v1*A1
      m2= rho2*v2*A2

      #conservation of mass states that the sum of mass flow rates in equal the mass flow rate out
      m_out= m1+m2
      print('The mass flow rate of the outlet in the system is'+ str(np.around(m_out)) + 'kg/m^3')
      """,
      "explanation": "This code calculates the outlet mass flow rate of the system, using the law of conservation of mass and known mass flow rate equation: m= pAv, where p = density (rho) of the fluid, A = Area of the opening, and v= velocity of the fluid."
  }
},
{
  "question": "Find the difference in pressure within a pipe that is 5000 meters long and a diameter of 2.5 meters. The fluid has a viscosity of 0.0035 kg/(m*s) and travels at velocity of 38 m/s.",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      L= 5000 # length of pipe
      v= 38 #bulk velocity of the fluid
      mew= 0.0035 # viscosity of the fluid
      d = 2.5 # diameter of the pipe

      # utilize the Hagen-Poiseuille equation to calculate pressure loss through a pipe
      m1= rho1*v1*A1
      delta_P = (8*L*v*mew)/((d/2)**2)

      print('The pressure loss across the pipe equals to ' + str(np.around(delta_P)) + ' Pa')
      """,
      "explanation": "This code calculates the pressure loss through a lengthy pipe using the Hagen-Poiseuille equation, using known information about the pipe's length, radius, experienced viscosity of the fluid, and speed of the fluid."
  }  
},
{
  "question": "A cyclic, nuclear powerplant uses nuclear reactions and the atmosphere to generate electricity. The efficiency of the system comes from using a hot reservoir created by the nuclear reaction and a cold reservoir created by the atmosphere around the reactor. Calculate the thermal efficiency of this reactor if the nuclear reaction produces a temperature of 205 degrees Celsius and the atmosphere has a temperature of 15 degrees Celsius.",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      Th= 205  # temperature of hot reservoir in Celsius
      Tc= 15   # temperature of cold reservoir in Celsius


      # Convert the temperatures from Celsius to Kelvin
      Th= Th+ 273.15
      Tc= Tc+ 273.15
      # Calculate the efficiency of the heat exchanger using the equation 
      Eta= 1 - (Th/Tc)
      print('The efficiency of this powerplant is ' + str(np.around(Eta)))
      """,
      "explanation": "The efficiency of a heat engine like the one in this example is solved using code that converts the temperature from Celsius to Kelvin and calculates the efficiency of the engine using the equation: Eta= 1- (temperature of hot reservoir)/(temperature of cold reservoir).",
      "reference": "https://phys.libretexts.org/Bookshelves/University_Physics/University_Physics_(OpenStax)/Book%3A_University_Physics_II_-_Thermodynamics_Electricity_and_Magnetism_(OpenStax)/04%3A_The_Second_Law_of_Thermodynamics/4.03%3A_Heat_Engines#:~:text=steam%2Dengine%20trains.-,Figure%204.3.,working%20substance%20through%20a%20cycle."
  }  
},
{
  "question": "Find the required rate of heat supplied by the heat exchanger to extract 4000 watts of energy from the cold space of a freezer. The freezer takes in heat at 750 degrees Celsius and has a cold space with a temperature of -20 degrees Celsisu. Additionally, heat is reject from the freezer at 10 degrees Celsius",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      T1= 750 # Temperature of hot reservoir
      T2= -20 # Temperature of cold reservoir
      T3= 10 # Temperature of heat expelled to environment

      # Convert all temperatures from Celsius to Kelvin 
      T1= 750+ 273.15
      T2= (-20)+ 273.15
      T3= 10+ 273.15
      # Use the Claussius inequality equation to calculate the minimum heat supply rate
      # Q1/T1 + Q2/T2 - (Q1+Q2)/T3 <= 0
      # Solving for Q1, we get: Q1/Q2 >= ((1/T2)-(1/T3)) / ((1/T3)-(1/T1))
      Q1= [((1/T2)-(1/T3)) / ((1/T3)-(1/T1))] * Q2

      print('The minimum rate of heat supply from the source of heat is ' + str(np.around(Q1)) + 'Watts ')
      """,
      "explanation": "This code calculates the minimum heat supply for a freezer and from the heat source using the Claussius equation set-up."
  }    
},
{
  "question": "Find the flow conditions downstream of a shock (mach and pressuce) with the given upstream properties: mach upstream is 2.2, the pressure upstream is 68,000 pascals. Assume gamma is 1.4.",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      M1= 2.2 # mach upstream
      P1 = 68000 # pressure in pascals upstream
      gamma= 1.4


      # First calculate the mach downstream using the known normal shock equation for mach relations
      M2_squared= (1+((gamma - 1)/2)*M1**2)/(gamma*M1**2 - ((gamma - 1)/2))
      M2= np.sqrt(M2)

      # Next calculate the pressure downstream using the known normal shock equations for pressure ratio relations
      P2_P1_ratio= (((2*gamma)/(gamma +1))*M1**2) - ((gamma-1)/(gamma+1))
      P2= P2_P1_ratio* P1
      print('The mach downstream of the shock is ' + str(np.around(M2)) + ' and the pressure downstream of the shock is ' + str(np.around(P2))+ ' Pa')
      """,
      "explanation": "This code checks the downstream conditions for mach and pressure using the given mach and pressure upstream and using the known relations for these properties in terms of normal shocks."
  }  
},
{
  "question": "Calculate the mach value of a fluid through a nozzle experiencing a temperature of 455 degrees Kelvin and a speed of 227 m/s.",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      Temp = 455 # temperature of the fluid in the nozzle
      v = 227 # speed of the fluid in the nozzle
      R= 287 # gas constant

      #assume gamma is 1.4 for this problem
      gamma = 1.4
      # Use the equation for mach: M= v/a and noting that a = sqrt(gamma*R*Temp) gives us:
      a= np.sqrt(gamma*R*Temp)
      M= v/a

      print('The mach speed for this fluid is' + str(np.around(M)) + 'within the nozzle')
      """,
      "explanation": "This code calculates the mach speed of a fluid in a nozzle using the given temperature and fluid speed, as well as using assumptions about the values of gamma and the gas constant."
  }  
},
{
  "question": "A gas with a gamma value of 1.22 is compressed asiabatically to a fourth of its intiial volume. Calculate the pressure and temperature after the compression if the inital values are 50000 pascals and 225 degrees Kelvin. Additionally assume that this adiabatic process is reversible.",
  "answer": {
      "code": """
      import numpy as np
      
      gamma= 1.22 # gamma value of the gas
      T1= 225 # intiial temperature of the gas before the process
      P1 = 50000# initial pressure of the gas before the process
      V1= 1 # initial volume of the gas
      V2 = 0.25 # volume of the gas after compression


      # Acknowledge that the adiabatic process is also reversible and thus isentropic. With this isentropic relations may be used:
      P2_P1_ratio = (V1/V2)**gamma
      P2= P1* P2_P1_ratio
      T2_T1_ratio = (V1/V2)**(gamma-1)
      T2= T1*T2_T1_ratio

      print('The gas has a temperature of ' + str(np.around(T2)) + ' degrees Kelvin and a pressure of '+ str(np.around(P2)) + 'Pa' )
      """,
      "explanation": "This code calculates the resulting temperature and pressure of an isentropic process using the relations known for this sort of process and applying the equations to solve."
  }  
}
]